SAMAR OMAR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Junior Front End Web Developer with a passion for learning and growing. experienced in JavaScript, React JS, and Axios. As well as a junior backend developer using NodeJS. With a background in Java, and OOP.

I bring strong skills in team working, fast learning, and problem solving that help software companies in reaching their goals in less time. Always motivated and excited to improve myself and my skills in every possible way.

CONTACT

- +90 505 052 9560
- samaromm98@gmail.com
- Linkedin
- Github
- Portfolio

INFORMATION

□ Female

LANGUAGES

Arabic (Native) English (superior) Turkish (Beginner)

EDUCATION

Talentvar Bootcamp - 2020

+ Back End Web Development (Mongodb, NodeJS)

2 months backend development program. Learn by directly working on the main project.

Re:Coded Bootcamp (Re:Coded + Flatiron School) - 2020

+ Front End Web Development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React) 5 month intense web development program run by Re:Coded with Flatiron School's curriculum.

Üsküdar University - Istanbul, Turkey (2017 - 2021)

+ Bachelor's Degree: Software Engineering.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

E-Bursum, Istanbul, Turkey

Junior Developer, 8/2020 - present

- + Re-built the front-end side of the company's website using HTML & Java Script without frameworks.
- + The pages I built have been integrated, sent to production, and are fully working now.
- + Received positive reactions from the clients.
- + Currently working on a huge website for the company with a lot of options using React, and Axios. Expected to go live this year.

Re:Coded Labs, Istanbul, Turkey

Junior Developer Intern, 12/2019 - 5/2020

- + Worked with teams, and in pairs to build the front-end side of various projects.
- + Contributed to the teams with my knowledge of Algorithms and general programming.

Üsküdar University, Istanbul, Turkey

Teaching Assistant, 2/2020 - 4/2020

- + Work with 1st and 2nd year students to help them understand algorithms and basic programming using Java, and C++.
- + Courses: Software Constructions, Introduction to Java, OOP II.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

E-Bursum website - Link

The website of a Turkish company the provides scholarships and internships opportunities for students.

- + Worked on the students' profile and evaluation pages.
- + Used HTML, PhP for frontend, SASS, and JavaScript without framework.
- + Built tables, pagination, and stories components using html and css only.

My Space - Github | Demo

This website is my own space to present my personal information!

- + Designed 4 different pages to present my info: About, CV, Projects, Contact.
- + Utilized React framework to create the project.
- + Implemented mdbootstrap library for the design.
- + Used Formspree to link the contact page with my email.

Page of Youth - Github | Demo

A planner website where you can save your schedule for each day and enter a diary/note.

- + Worked with React framework to design the front-end side.
- + Used Firebase for authentication and as a database.
- + Installed React big calendar for the homepage.

NA'AMAL - Demo

Website for an organization that provides remote work opportunities for refugees, by linking them to interested companies.

- + Used React framework for building front end side of pages that describe goals, and operations related to Na'amal, and how to contact them.
- + Fetched articles from Na'aml's WordPress API to build a blog for them
- + Implemented Bootstrap library for the designs.
- + Practiced Jest for building tests of the code.

Bookmark backend

CRUD the user profiles of an interactive website to bookmark important YouTube videos and resources and share the knowledge with other users. (2 months group project)

- + Practiced mongodb to save the data of the users in a database.
- + Implemented NestJS to create/get/delete/update user profiles.
- + Created CRUD for Education section where the user can add their educational background.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JS, React framework, Axios:

+ Good knowledge, have done different projects, able to create websites from scratch, or use libraries and open source.

Java:

+ Years of study, confident enough, very good knowledge of OOP in Java, able to create large scale systems.

Sass:

+Moderate knowledge, used in internship.

NodeJs, Sequelize, SQL, NestJS and mongodb:

+ Beginner.